My name is Brandon.
The first step to getting on the wall is to tie in.
When you approach the wall, look up, separate the ropes and grab the rope closest the wall.
This is going to be the climber's rope.
Next, grab the very end of that rope in your right hand.
Pull an arm's span of slack through.
Next step, make a pinch in the rope with the end of the rope on the right side and drop it from your right hand.
Double check to make certain that the end of the rope is in the right side of the loop, wrap the rope clock wise around the loop.
Take the very end of the rope, pass it to the front of the loop, pull through.
When you pull the knot tight, it should come out looking like an 8.
This called the figure 8 knot.
What you're going to do next is retrace this knot to your harness tying yourself in.